<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Random Thoughts on Ryan&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://espe0606.github.io/categories/random-thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Random Thoughts on Ryan&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 11:57:33 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://espe0606.github.io/categories/random-thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Updating</title>
      <link>https://espe0606.github.io/posts/2022/12/updating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 11:57:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://espe0606.github.io/posts/2022/12/updating/</guid>
      <description>I have been working on a LSTM model these days, however the progress is not going very well. There are several problems I still need to figure out.
(Graph source: Towards Data Science,TDS, by Michael Phi)
The model I built seems fit on stocks with more &amp;rsquo;linear&amp;rsquo; price fluctuation, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t work well on those with &amp;rsquo;exponential&amp;rsquo; price fluctuation (no matter upside or downside).
Input parameters are not enough. Right now, I&amp;rsquo;m using time series of past close price for the forecasting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How will A.I. affect some so called &#39;creative&#39; jobs?</title>
      <link>https://espe0606.github.io/posts/2022/12/how-will-a.i.-affect-some-so-called-creative-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 12:21:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://espe0606.github.io/posts/2022/12/how-will-a.i.-affect-some-so-called-creative-jobs/</guid>
      <description>Today I reconnected with an old friend. We knewn each other when I was studying Economics in U.S. She was an associate professor at that time. We started an interesting conversation about A.I. by talking about one professor that we both liked a lot.
She is a CFA certificate holder and now teaching financial course in a top-tier University, but her knowledge on Data Science and A.I. still surprised me. We both believe that not only those blue-collar jobs will be mostly replaced by A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first post</title>
      <link>https://espe0606.github.io/posts/2022/11/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 14:31:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://espe0606.github.io/posts/2022/11/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Hello, welcome to my blog!!
My name is Ryan, now living in Barcelona. Previously I worked in Financial sector, especially in PE&amp;amp;VC for more than 10 years, then I wrote a book and got it published in mainland China and HongKong. Now I worked as a freelancer data scientist and will be an enthusiast of A.I and machine learning in the future.
Since most of my time will be dedicated to learn data science, machine learning and neural networks, this blog will be mainly utilized to record my study progress and some interesting topics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
