<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SQL on Ryan&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://espe0606.github.io/tags/sql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SQL on Ryan&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 17:33:37 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://espe0606.github.io/tags/sql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Calculated fields and data manipulation</title>
      <link>https://espe0606.github.io/posts/2022/12/calculated-fields-and-data-manipulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 17:33:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://espe0606.github.io/posts/2022/12/calculated-fields-and-data-manipulation/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes we need to manipulate the data stored in a table. For example: retrieving converted, calculated, or reformatted data. This is where calculated fields come in.
Concatenating Fields Concatenate means joining values together (by appending them to each other) to form a single long value. The SELECT statement can help us with this task. In SQL SELECT statements, we can concatenate columns using a special operator. Depending on what DBMS we are using, this can be a plus sign (+) or two pipes (||).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methods of filtering data</title>
      <link>https://espe0606.github.io/posts/2022/12/methods-of-filtering-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 22:23:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://espe0606.github.io/posts/2022/12/methods-of-filtering-data/</guid>
      <description>The most basic command for filtering data is using SELECT statement’s WHERE clause to specify search conditions. Within a SELECT statement, data is filtered by specifying search criteria in the WHERE clause. The WHERE clause is specified right after the table name (the FROM clause) as follows:
select column_1, column_2 from table where column_1 &amp;gt; 5
Caution:
When using both ORDER BY and WHERE clauses, make sure that ORDER BY comes after the WHERE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic ideas of SQL, retrieving and sorting data</title>
      <link>https://espe0606.github.io/posts/2022/12/basic-ideas-of-sql-retrieving-and-sorting-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 13:23:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://espe0606.github.io/posts/2022/12/basic-ideas-of-sql-retrieving-and-sorting-data/</guid>
      <description>SQL is one kind of DBMS (Database Management System). For the purpose of data analyze, database (DB) is a collection of data stored in some organized fashion. The simplest way to think of it is to imagine a database as a container. The container is simply a physical location to store data, regardless of what that data is or how it is organized. SQL means Structured Query Language which designed specifically for communicating with databases.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
